{"test_questions": [[{"question": "In a frequency counter, what happens at high frequencies when the sampling interval is too long?", "opta": "The counter works fine.", "optb": "The counter undercounts the frequency.", "optc": "The measurement is less precise.", "optd": "The counter overflows.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, when does the PM indicator go high?", "opta": "Never", "optb": "Going from 11:59:59 to 12:00:00", "optc": "Going from 12:59:59 to 01:00:00", "optd": "On the falling edge of the clock after enable goes high", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How is the output frequency related to the sampling interval of a frequency counter?", "opta": "Directly with the sampling interval", "optb": "Inversely with the sampling interval", "optc": "More precision with longer sampling interval", "optd": "Less precision with longer sampling interval", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an HDL application of a stepper motor, after an up/down counter is built what is done next?", "opta": "Build the sequencer", "optb": "Test it on a simulator", "optc": "Test the decoder", "optd": "Design an intermediate integer variable", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a digital clock application, the basic frequency must be divided down to:", "opta": "1 Hz.", "optb": "60 Hz.", "optc": "100 Hz.", "optd": "1000 Hz.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, what does the data signal define?", "opta": "The row and column encoded data", "optb": "The ring encoded data", "optc": "The freeze locator data", "optd": "The ring counter data", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the ring counter in the HDL keypad application do when a key is pressed?", "opta": "Count to find the row", "optb": "Freeze", "optc": "Count to find the column", "optd": "Start the D flip-flop", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, the purpose of the frequency prescaler is to:", "opta": "find the basic frequency.", "optb": "transform a 60 pps input to a 1 pps timing signal.", "optc": "prevent the clock from exceeding 12:59:59.", "optd": "allow the BCD display to have a value from 00\u201359.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a step that should be followed in project management?", "opta": "Overall definition", "optb": "System documentation", "optc": "Synthesis and testing", "optd": "System integration", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, what does the preset state of the ring counter define?", "opta": "The proper output of the column encoder", "optb": "The NANDing of the rows", "optc": "The NANDing of the columns", "optd": "The proper output of the row encoder", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In an HDL stepper motor design, why is there more than one mode?", "opta": "To change the speed of the stepper motor", "optb": "To change the direction of the stepper motor", "optc": "To direct drive the stepper motor", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a major block of an HDL frequency counter?", "opta": "Display register", "optb": "Decoder/display", "optc": "Timing and control unit", "optd": "Bit shifter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In a full-step sequence involving two flip-flops driving four coils of a stepper motor, how far will the stepper motor step?", "opta": "90\u00b0", "optb": "45\u00b0", "optc": "30\u00b0", "optd": "15\u00b0", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a step used to define the scope of an HDL project?", "opta": "Are the inputs and outputs active HIGH or active LOW?", "optb": "A clear vision of how to make each block work", "optc": "What are the speed requirements?", "optd": "How many bits of data are needed?", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, what is the frequency of the MOD-6 counter in the minutes section?", "opta": "1 pulse per minute", "optb": "6 pulses per minute", "optc": "10 pulses per minute", "optd": "1 pulse per hour", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why should a real hardware functional test be performed on the HDL stepper motor design?", "opta": "To check the speed of the software", "optb": "To check the current levels in the motor", "optc": "To check the voltage levels of the real outputs", "optd": "To provide a fully operational system", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What does the major block of an HDL code emulation of a keypad include?", "opta": "A sequencer", "optb": "A clock", "optc": "A multiplexer", "optd": "A ring counter", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The accuracy of the frequency counter depends on the:", "opta": "system clock frequency.", "optb": "number of displayed digits.", "optc": "sampling rate.", "optd": "display update rate.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the frequency counter, if the clock generator produces a 100 kHz system clock signal, how many decade counters are required to measure 1 Hz?", "opta": "6", "optb": "5", "optc": "4", "optd": "3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What must a stepper motor HDL application include?", "opta": "Variables and processes", "optb": "Types and bits", "optc": "Counters and decoders", "optd": "Sequencers and multiplexers", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a step in strategic planning for HDL development?", "opta": "There must be a way to test each piece.", "optb": "Each block must fit together to make up the whole system.", "optc": "The names of each input and output must be known.", "optd": "The exact operation of each block must be thoroughly defined and understood.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the frequency counter, when is the new count stored in the display register?", "opta": "After disabling the counter", "optb": "When the count buffer is full", "optc": "After the sample interval is set", "optd": "When the timing and control block has put it there", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What are two ways to remember the current state of a counter in VHDL?", "opta": "With FUNCTIONS and PROCESS", "optb": "With counters and timers", "optc": "With SIGNAL and VARIABLE", "optd": "With bit types", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the digital clock project, what type of counter is used to count to 59 seconds?", "opta": "MOD-60", "optb": "MOD-6", "optc": "BCD", "optd": "BCD followed by a MOD-6", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, when all columns are HIGH, the ring counter is enabled and counting, and dav is LOW, what is the status of the d outputs?", "opta": "On", "optb": "Off", "optc": "Hi-Z", "optd": "1011", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the frequency counter, what is the function of the Schmitt trigger circuit?", "opta": "To reduce input noise", "optb": "To condition the input signal", "optc": "To convert non-square waveforms", "optd": "To provide a usable signal to the display unit", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "List three basic blocks in the digital clock project.", "opta": "MOD-60, MOD-12 counters", "optb": "MOD-5, MOD-10, MOD-12 counters", "optc": "MOD-60, MOD-10 counters", "optd": "MOD-6, MOD-12, and MOD-10 counters", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When designing an HDL digital system, which is the worst mistake one can make?", "opta": "Concluding that a fundamental block works perfectly", "optb": "Failing to provide proper documentation", "optc": "Adding blocks of code prior to testing them", "optd": "Overlooking a possible VARIABLE", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the keypad application, just after the 4 ms mark the simulation imitates the release of the key by changing the column value back to F hex, which causes the d output to go into its Hi-Z state. On the next rising clock edge, what happens to dav?", "opta": "It goes HIGH.", "optb": "It goes LOW.", "optc": "It goes to Hi-Z.", "optd": "It goes to 1111H.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "For the frequency counter, which is not a control signal from the control and timing block?", "opta": "Clear", "optb": "Enable", "optc": "Reset", "optd": "Store", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}